[Music]
hi everyone my name's debbie king and
here with me today is gary westcott and
steve hichman and we're all really
excited to bring you a taste of the new
insights functionality that's within the
intelligent performance management
oracle solution
this has been actually delivered to you
in the november release for all of our
epm enterprise
solution
clients
so before we jump into the tool we're
going to just talk talk through the
evolution of planning and you may your
organization may be at any stage on this
evolutionary
line but a lot will have started with
and possibly still use manual or excel
methods to do your planning
that's been improved over time with
driver-based and historical trend
analysis to try and ac more accurately
get to where your forecast needs to be
but that can still take time with a lot
of data particularly if you're still
using manual methods to do that
auto predict is the functionality where
you can look at historical information
to predict where you are in the future
which has been evolving um really
quickly but where we're at today and
what we want to jump into
is where machine learning prediction
is is going to help us out to get to
that nirvana that we often talk about of
a zero touch forecast but at the very
least to get a light touch and more
accurate and fast forecasting and
budgeting
outcome for your organization
so
just in line with that evolution what
technology providers have been trying to
do is actually originally give
give the accountants give the people
more time to analyze the data and
i mean that's been great and it has had
a lot of benefit but as you can see just
from this very simple
um chart of account
combination here so think about 200
accounts 100 entities
50 products 100 customers it's 100
million data combinations that you would
have to have a look at to find where
variances might be and
as highlighted here if you have um
something materially over in sydney or
and under in melbourne it'll be needle
in a haystack stuff trying to get down
to that variance and often you'll just
skip over it and look at things at a
higher level so
machine
learning this particular tool is going
to help us out by providing those that
analysis and then we can look at the
analysis in a bit more detail
[Music]
the insights functionality is built on
the cornerstone of
is predictive planning is cornerstone of
this functionality so that's the
foundation of how this inside stuff's
been working
and you actually have had
the if with the planning tool um
predictive planning has been available
for some time
and
i guess insights just takes that to the
to the next level where you
are shown the inside behind some of that
prediction so
before we
actually jump in and have a look at the
tool
in play so gary's standing by there's
just a few things you need to know this
was
as i said before delivered in the
november release so ready at your
fingertips it is for epm enterprise
customers only and you do need the red
wood theme
required and i think we've said that and
steve online has said that at quite a
few of these
um
information sessions where you get more
functionality by enabling the redwood
theme and it's necessary for ipm
the navigation flows very cute little
artificial intelligent robot um to guide
you through to where insights will live
but i think importantly and you'll see
it in the tool
plain english user-friendly um end user
focused insights to then have a look at
and
you can determine whether or not you
want to use that prediction
very nice clean um graphical
user interface as well so without me
just talking about it i'm going to hand
over to gary to show you the tool in
action so thanks gary thanks debbie
so we're open at the home screen and to
get to the insights you click on the ipm
navigation flow
and go to insights
and so there are a number of insights
that come up when you go to the inside
screen and as you can see we've got
there's multiple types of insights and
but and that's going to grow but we've
got i'm only showing two of them and the
two i'm showing you guys the forecast
variants and buyers which is just
relates to the material differences in
actual versus forecast but the one i'm
really going to concentrate on is the
prediction insight which so here you can
see we've got two prediction insights
one for sydney one for melbourne
melbourne is
um lower than the forecast and sydney is
higher than the forecast so as debbie
said at a higher level that they're
going to negate each other out so you
may not actually see that if you're just
doing your analysis at a um aggregate
level
so i'll go and click into the sydney
insight
okay so for the sydney insight you can
see that there are two lines here one
sub-base prediction and the other one's
are forecast the base prediction is the
actual machine learning what it's
actually predicting the forecast should
be and as you can see it's got some
seasonality in it
which our forecast which we use during
doing our driver models or inputting
hasn't got so
it
has actually done a good job of
forecasting so you can actually see the
dollar amounts down here as well so you
can say okay you've forecasted 400k flat
but the actual base prediction is using
has come up with a different amount so
it is about actually 26 higher than what
you forecast
you can actually
go over and update this forecast if you
wanted to
so you can add comments when you do it
you can dismiss the inside if you don't
think it's materially different or you
and or you can open as an ad hoc form
you can also do an override once you've
updated the forecast and to say okay you
still want to have a little bit of a
difference there so you can actually do
an override so i'm just going to update
the forecast
and oh you can actually write a comment
there but i won't
and now you can see there's only one
line that's because the forecast and the
base prediction have now become the same
so you've updated your forecast
below so now you've got the machine
learning
so how do you configure that you go up
to the top screen to do the configure
and i'll click on the one i've called
predict
and see this one i've chosen for auto
predict and prediction insights
and to define the slice you can
go into the define size so this shows
that you're using actuals and you can
say how many historical years do you
want to use you can use
four if you want to five three depending
on how much many actuals you've got and
the other side just shows the forecast
data and what you're going to predict
so you go to configure
what we're doing is saying okay you
should come up as an insight if the
threshold of variance is more than 12
if it's not then it doesn't come up so
you can also have advanced insights for
the data scientists out there which
shows actual different metrics that you
can use to calculate that
but i'm just sticking to the simple
basic 12 percent
next you go to settings
so the settings one shows the magnitude
of the threshold so if you're saying
okay there's a 30 increase you're going
to put that as high if you've got a 10
percent increase that's low so that just
shows
what which ones you can going to sit at
higher so you can actually concentrate
on them more than the lower ones
so that's how you how you set up the
insight
you can you can also at the same time
oracle has released
machine learning models
so
this allows organizations to bring their
own model into
the system using their own machine
learning model so and you can just
import that in there as well
we'll hand over to steve to wrap it up
from here
thank you gary so steve speaking um
we we're pretty excited about this
functionality which has sort of been in
the making um for a little while there's
been a number of kind of foundational
blocks and this is really starting to
show
sort of a significant peak into the
future so it's good already
there's more to come
as you kind of hopefully saw very easy
to use very much targeted at the
business unit user
trying to simplify and
add efficiency
if you would like to know more there's a
couple of customer connect sessions
highlighted there both of them are
approximately an hour of time including
a bit more on the bring your own machine
learning that gary very briefly touched
on
and or feel free to reach out to us for
more information thank you very much
[Music]